<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Drush | Fractions on my timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://hagzag.github.io/blog/categories/drush/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hagzag.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-10T08:18:02+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://hagzag.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Haggai Philip Zagury]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[hagzag@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing drupal with Drush (Drupal Shell)]]></title>
    <link href="http://hagzag.github.io/blog/2010/08/27/TManage-Drupal-With-Drush/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-27T09:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://hagzag.github.io/blog/2010/08/27/TManage-Drupal-With-Drush</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="/assets/images/drush.png" title="&lsquo;Drush Logo&rsquo;" >Well, those of you who know me now I&rsquo;ve become a very big Drupal fan and one of the tools that will make your life much easier is <a href="http://drupal.org/project/drush">Drush</a>. Drush short for Drupal Shell and it works just like one.</p>

<p>Download <a href="http://drupal.org/project/drush">Drush</a> and add it to your path &ndash; assuming you are using unix/linux (if you are using Windows then a <a href="http://drupal.org/node/330023">tutorial can be found here</a> it actually works I&rsquo;ve tried it).</p>

<p>Drush dl will download latest stable Drupal to the current location ($PWD) and you are ready for your Drupal installation &ndash; OK so the bootstrap process isn&rsquo;t that simple because you still need to setup your environment (http, php, mysql/some other supported DB) but still it takes are of the downloading part making sure you are using the latest version etc.</p>

<p>The real power in Drush comes when you have a large site with a bundle of distributed modules, and you need to start managing dependencies and versions. The problem with the standard way, <a href="http://yoursite/admin/build/modules,">http://yoursite/admin/build/modules,</a> is:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>It takes a year to load the page</p></li>
<li><p>In order to solve dependencies you need to:</p></li>
<li><p>Take a note of what you need to download</p></li>
<li>Go to <a href="http://drupal.org/project/modules">http://drupal.org/project/modules</a></li>
<li>Search and download</li>
<li>Upload to your server</li>
</ul>


<p>This seems like to much work &ndash; Drush does all that for you, just cd to your Drupal installation directory run <em><strong>drush dl <module name\></strong></em> and Drush will get it and extract it for you under your sites/default/modules directory.</p>

<p>Another bonus is you don&rsquo;t get stuck with those tar.gz files you need to manually remove after enabling the module.</p>

<p>Thats not all, <em><strong>drush en <module name\></strong></em> &amp; <em><strong>drush up <module name\> </strong></em>will enable the module (again no need to navigate to sites/all/modules and use the check-box.</p>

<p>If you run <em><strong>drush up</strong> </em>with no args Drush will attempt to update your Drupal installation and all the modules that need updates &ndash; be careful here for you do not want to break anything, for the upgrade includes your database tables !!!._<br/>
_</p>

<p>The last &ldquo;bonus&rdquo; is that Drush stores all the updated modules / files in &lt;site_root>/backup so you have all the old / updated data backed up in case you need to rollback (been there done that).</p>

<p>For the full list of what drush can do for you &ndash; for exmaple if you rn multipul sites from the same drupal case and other options .. see drush help:</p>

<p><code>_[me@mybox modules]# drush --help  
Execute a drush command. Run \</code>drush help [command]` to view command-specific help.</p>

<p>Examples:<br/>
 drush dl cck zen                          Download CCK module and Zen theme.                  <br/>
 drush &mdash;uri=<a href="http://example.com">http://example.com</a> status     Show status command for the example.com multi-site. <br/>
 drush help &mdash;pipe                         A space delimited list of commands                 </p>

<p>Options:<br/>
 -r <path>, &mdash;root=<path>                  Drupal root directory to use (default: current directory)                <br/>
 -l <uri>, &mdash;uri=<a href="http://example.com%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0">http://example.com%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0%C2%A0</a> URI of the drupal site to use (only needed in multisite environments)    <br/>
 -v, &mdash;verbose                             Display extra information about the command.                             <br/>
 -d, &mdash;debug                               Display even more information, including internal messages.              <br/>
 -q, &mdash;quiet                               Hide all output                                                          <br/>
 -y, &mdash;yes                                 Assume &lsquo;yes&rsquo; as answer to all prompts                                    <br/>
 -n, &mdash;no                                  Assume &lsquo;no&rsquo; as answer to all prompts                                     <br/>
 -s, &mdash;simulate                            Simulate all relevant actions (don&rsquo;t actually change the system)         <br/>
 -i, &mdash;include                             A list of paths to search for drush commands                             <br/>
 -c, &mdash;config                              Specify a config file to use. See example.drushrc.php                    <br/>
 -u, &mdash;user                                Specify a user to login with. May be a name or a number.                 <br/>
 -b, &mdash;backend                             Hide all output and return structured data (internal use only).          <br/>
 -p, &mdash;pipe                                Emit a compact representation of the command for scripting.              <br/>
 &mdash;nocolor                                 Suppress color highlighting on log messages.                             <br/>
 &mdash;show-passwords                          Show database passwords in commands that display connection information. <br/>
 -h, &mdash;help                                This help system.                                                        <br/>
 &mdash;php                                     The absolute path to your PHP intepreter, if not &lsquo;php&rsquo; in the path. _`</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
